<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?><communities><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/10038</handle><id>49</id><name>Association for Portuguese and Lusophone Studies</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>3</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2911</handle><id>36</id><name>Barbara Godard Collection</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>27</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;P align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Photo: James Gillespie&lt;/P&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Barbara Thompson Godard (1941-2010) was Professor of English, French, Social and Political Thought, and Women's Studies at York University, where she was named to the Avi Bennett Historica Chair in Canadian Literature.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;With a B.A. from the University of Toronto and an M.A. from l'Université de Montréal, Dr. Godard completed her doctorate at l'Université de Bordeaux and began teaching at York in 1971 as a visiting assistant professor.  She was hired into a tenure-track position in 1976.  A prolific and gregarious scholar, she published eight books, 80 book chapters and 115 articles and catalogue entries.  She translated the major writers of Québec feminism, including Nicole Brossard, Yolande Villemaire and Louky Bersianik.  She also served as editor or on the editorial board of 22 journals.  She was a founding co-editor of the feminist literary periodical &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tessera&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a contributing editor of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open Letter and The Semiotic Review of Books&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;and the book review editor for &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Topia:  A Canadian Journal of Cultural Studies&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.  She also made longstanding contributions to &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources for Feminist Research&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Voix et Images&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;ECW&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, among others.  A copy of Professor Godard's &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Curriculum Vitae&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  is included among the documents of this collection.&lt;/p&gt;  &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Barbara Godard inspired her colleagues and students through her critical creativity and her unwavering commitment to interrogating and producing the conditions for full civic engagement in the university and in the public sphere.&lt;/p&gt;  &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;On December 5 &amp; 6, 2008, a gathering was organized by students, former students, colleagues, and friends of Barbara Godard to honour her, not only for her resounding impact on Canadian literature through her work as translator, theoretician and critic, but also for her immense contribution, through teaching and collaboration, in helping to create an avant-garde community of women writers and artists in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Entitled &quot;Inspiring Collaborations,&quot; the symposium began with a joint keynote address by Nicole Brossard and Daphne Marlatt (both pre-eminent figures in the French and English Canadian literary scene), and included two large round-table discussions, the first centered on &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tessera&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a review of literature and criticism of which Barbara was a founding editor, the second involving past and present students speaking about her influence on them.  Interspersed with these events were musical and vocal performances and poetry readings, a screening of an early film involving Barbara as a student, along with exhibitions of visual and video art, all by people who in some way were inspired by her (see the copy of the programme for &quot;Inspiring Collaborations&quot; included in this collection).&lt;/p&gt;  &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;It was by no means certain that Professor Godard would be able to attend the 2008 celebrations because, in the summer and fall of that year, she was exhausted by intensive chemotherapy treatments against cancer, and was worried about the effects of excitement and a crowd of people on her battered immune system.  But she did attend, for hours at a time, in a striking outfit with a broad-brimmed black hat, supplying from the floor precise names and dates to roundtable participants when their memories faltered.  She also found time and energy to prepare a moving and witty communication of thanks at the end of the day (included as one of the texts in this collection).&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Flushed with the emotional and intellectual high of the December event, organizers decided to look into preparing some kind of published festschrift for Barbara, involving in the first instance and as much as possible the proceedings of the December, 2008 event, including visual and video art, as well as a more formal, international, academic collection of essays reflecting Barbara's interests.  It was early decided that Yorkspace was the most suitable site for the &quot;Inspiring Collaboration&quot; proceedings.  Slowly, we have been able to post a selection of texts and visual material, and we intend to present as much documentary evidence as we can, including excerpts from a film made by Brenda Longfellow and associates during the event.  This collection is not intended to present academic or reviewed publications, and in our editing we have tried to respect the spontaneity of the event.&lt;/p&gt;  &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Yorkspace also seems to be the logical place for an eventual posting of the complete writings of Barbara Godard, especially of unpublished articles or those now difficult to find.   But such a project, as anyone who knows her work will agree, is an enormous undertaking that will take some time.  This collection might also be the place to include later articles and hommages to Barbara that do not fit the parameters of the printed festschrifts.&lt;/p&gt;  &#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the second part of the mandate has gone forward, with a call for proposals, a heartening response, a primary selection, and the possibility of two printed publications:  one in book form, and another as a special number of the periodical, &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open Letter&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.  Yorkspace will, of course, include information on those eventual printed publications, if not the texts themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the noon hour of May 10, 2011, a brief ceremony was held to mark the naming of a section of St. Mary Street (leading west of Bay, just south of Danforth) as Barbara Godard Way.  This initiative was proposed by Barbara Sternberg, encouraged by Cheryl Sourkes, and seen through City Hall by Councillor Kristyn Wong-Tam.  All three spoke eloquently about Barbara to the people assembled.  Pictures were taken by a City of Toronto photographer, and by Cheryl Sourkes. See under &quot;texts&quot; addresses given by Barbara Sternberg and Cheryl Sourkes at that time. To view all items related to this ceremony, see the series: &lt;a href=&quot;http://pi.library.yorku.ca/dspace/handle/10315/2911/browse?value=Unveiling+Ceremony+of+Barbara+Godard+Way&amp;type=series&quot;&gt;Unveiling Ceremony of Barbara Godard Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/27722</handle><id>61</id><name>Canada-Mediterranean Centre</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>36</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/18071</handle><id>52</id><name>Canadian Studies -- Études canadiennes</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>35</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2892</handle><id>34</id><name>Centre for Atmospheric Chemistry</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>245</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/1266</handle><id>21</id><name>Centre for Research on Language Contact</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>147</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glendon.yorku.ca/crlc/&quot;&gt;Centre for Research on Language Contact (CRLC)&lt;/a&gt; brings together the research activities of the faculty members and students of York University who investigate various aspects of language contact at both societal and individual levels. Among the topics examined by CRLC members one can mention: second or multiple language acquisition, societal or individual bilingualism, inter-group relationships in bilingual or multilingual settings, minority language maintenance or loss, bilingual education, the role of language and cultural contact in language change, pidgin and Creole genesis, dialect mixture and the linguistic and cultural dimensions of translation. CRLC members investigate language contact from the perspective of several disciplines (e.g., linguistics, sociology, demography, psychology, political science, history and musicology) and in a variety of settings, Toronto and Ontario, other Canadian provinces and other countries throughout the world. The CRLC includes external members who are leading researchers in the field of Language Contact.&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/1</handle><id>1</id><name>Changing Urban Waterfronts</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>299</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;img src=&quot;/dspace/themes/YorkSpace/water.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing together researchers from social scientific, humanities and scientific disciplines, this project investigates Toronto's waterfront during the past hundred years. The project uses the ideas of social nature and political ecology to study the waterfront, a special place where land and water meet, as an interactive space in which the social and the natural are constantly remaking one another. That is, urban waterfronts are always both social and natural and need to be studied as such. The overarching question our research addresses is: How have various discourses and practices combined to produce and regulate Toronto's waterfront as a socio-economic and ecological space? We approach this question by observing that during the last few decades, policy makers, planners and developers have looked to waterfronts in North American and European cities as sites for massive urban revitalization projects that contribute to expanding the roles of metropolitan regions and the formation of new urban hierarchies in a globalized economy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;ACCESS TO DOCUMENTS IN THE &quot;PROJECT IMAGES AND NOTES&quot; COLLECTION IS RESTRICTED TO MEMBERS OF THE CHANGING URBAN WATERFRONTS RESEARCH GROUP.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Project Images and Notes&quot; collection is the private workspace for members of the Changing Urban Waterfronts research group. Access cannot be granted to non-project members.&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/8089</handle><id>42</id><name>Churchill Community of Knowledge</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>209</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;An online resource of data and media about the Town of Churchill, its people, Wapusk National Park, and the extensive research supported by the Churchill Northern Studies Centre. This Digital Archive is hosted by the Yorkspace Institutional Repository, York University, Toronto. The first collection in the project celebrates the life and work of Professor Bob Jefferies, who carried out field research in ecology in and near Churchill, for 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pi.library.yorku.ca/dspace/handle/10315/9274&quot;&gt;Robert L. Jefferies Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;How to submit an item:&#xD;
Undigitized items (lke your old Kodachrome slides) can be sent to Ms. Netta Untershats and her team for digitizing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We will send you a receipt for the items, and send them back to you after they are digitized. Please include any information about the item - in the case of photos, what, where, when and who? And, please remember to confirm in writing in an email or letter, that you are the owner of the image.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;QUESTIONS? For items related to Bob Jefferies and other La Pérouse Bay research and to send digitized items, please contact:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Dawn Bazely: dbazely@yorku.ca&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Netta Untershats: nettauntershats@osgoode.yorku.ca&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;For items relating to the broader Churchill community:&#xD;
Mike Goodyear and Leeann Fishback of the Churchill Northern Studies Centre, can advise you about items that do not directly relate to Prof. Jefferies’ life and research, but which do  relate to the broader Churchill community, including the Studies Centre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;goodyear@churchillscience.ca&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;fishback@churchillscience.ca&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;To browse by particlar area, please click on one of the hyperlinks below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pi.library.yorku.ca/dspace/handle/10315/8089/browse?value=Camp+Finney&amp;type=subject&quot;&gt;Camp Finney&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pi.library.yorku.ca/dspace/handle/10315/8089/browse?value=Hudson+Bay&amp;type=subject&quot;&gt;Hudson Bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pi.library.yorku.ca/dspace/handle/10315/8089/browse?value=La+P%C3%A9rouse+Bay&amp;type=subject&quot;&gt;La Pérouse Bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pi.library.yorku.ca/dspace/handle/10315/8089/browse?value=Wapusk+National+Park&amp;type=subject&quot;&gt;Wapusk National Park of Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/580</handle><id>9</id><name>Clara Thomas Archives and Special Collections</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>25677</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2803</handle><id>33</id><name>Dialectology</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>5</countItems><introductoryText>Materials related to the study of human language dialects</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/4566</handle><id>38</id><name>Division of Research and Innovation</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>232</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/26310</handle><id>56</id><name>Electronic Theses and Dissertations (ETDs)</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>1176</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;To submit an Electronic Thesis and Dissertation (ETD), visit the Faculty of Graduate Studies' &lt;a href=&quot;http://gradstudies.yorku.ca/current-students/thesis-dissertation/etd/&quot;&gt; How to Submit&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact the Faculty of Graduate Studies directly with any questions regarding ETDs. &lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2520</handle><id>27</id><name>Faculty of Education</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>12</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/6200</handle><id>40</id><name>Faculty of Environmental Studies</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>207</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/1276</handle><id>22</id><name>Faculty of Graduate Studies</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>1180</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2488</handle><id>26</id><name>Faculty of Health</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>319</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/6207</handle><id>41</id><name>Faculty of Liberal Arts and Professional Studies</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>56</countItems><introductoryText>Faculty of Liberal Arts and Professional Studies</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/899</handle><id>14</id><name>Faculty of Science</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>151</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2478</handle><id>25</id><name>Glendon</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>220</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2746</handle><id>32</id><name>Institute for Research and Innovation in Sustainability</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>48</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/28068</handle><id>62</id><name>International Association for the Study of the Culture of Cities (IASCC 2014)</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>4</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2900</handle><id>35</id><name>International Congress of Onomastic Sciences, ICOS XXIII</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>122</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/21985</handle><id>55</id><name>International Studies Symposium</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>5</countItems><introductoryText>The Glendon’s Student Annual International Studies Symposium is a project entirely conceived and managed by students. It was initiated during the 1995-1996 academic year by a group of highly motivated students, eager to deepen their knowledge and experience of foreign countries or regions and the relations between Canada and those countries or regions. So far, the Project has covered the following countries or regions: Cuba (1995-1996), China (1996-97), South Africa (1997-1998), the European Union (1998-1999), the Middle East (1999-2000), South East Asia (2000-2001), Brazil (2001-2002), Russia (2002-2003), India (2003-2004), The Great Lakes Regions of Central Africa (2004-2005), Mexico (2005-2006), Turkey (2006-2007), Egypt (2007-2008), Venezuela (2008-2009), Iran (2009-2010), Hispaniola (2010-2011), Germany (2011-2012), and Korea (2012-2013). The success of this project has enhanced the visibility, not only of the Department of International Studies, but also of Glendon College and York University as a whole, in Canada and abroad. The students have consistently been able to invite many distinguished speakers and guests to participate in the symposium, including foreign diplomats as well as Canadian federal ministers and renowned Canadian and international academics. The project has become a major event, forging links among various constituencies, notably the Glendon, York and outside academic community as well as the wider metropolitan community, in particular its immigrant population.&#xD;
&#xD;
This online community offers online access to digitized copies of the conference proceedings published for the symposiums focused on Mexico, Brazil, and Russia.</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/31797</handle><id>70</id><name>Jan Rehner Prize for Writing</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>7</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Jan Rehner Prize for Writing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Jan Rehner Prize for Writing was created in honour of University Professor Jan Rehner, a long-time member of York University’s Writing Department. For many years, Professor Rehner has introduced and inspired students to the study of writing, teaching students at all year levels. A University-wide AND a National 3M award teaching winner, she is as home tutoring one-on-one in the Writing Centre as she is in the lecture hall, and her careful, thoughtful feedback in tutorial and seminar has been greatly valued by her students for many years. Professor Rehner was also instrumental in the formation of the LA&amp;PS Writing Department, helping bring together the Writing Centre and the Professional Writing Program in her capacity as program coordinator in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Rehner teaches her students both to challenge dominant narratives, and to find their own voice as writers and persons. She encourages them to become critically aware of their society, and of their own writing process. This award was established in recognition of her ceaseless efforts to empower and embolden students as writers and citizens, and with the gratitude of the many students, colleagues, and friends met during her years of contribution to the Writing Department and to the University. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Competition Description&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Jan Rehner Prize for Writing is a student nominated, faculty-judged competition open to students who take Department of Writing courses. A winner and an honourable mention from 1000, 2000, 3000 and 4000 level courses are chosen in May of each year. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Submissions in any style, using any form, or from any genre may be nominated so long as their content is primarily text-based. Life writing, film criticism, podcast transcripts, reports, formal essays, and other kinds of writing are all welcome. Nominated papers must have received a final grade of an “A” or better (e.g. 80%+) and must be submitted without identifying information. The submissions assignment instructions are also required. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Both winners and runners-up receive an official transcript note, a gift card, and the opportunity to have their paper published online and permanently available on York's website.&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/32547</handle><id>72</id><name>LA&amp;PS Writing Prize</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>8</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;LA&amp;PS Writing Prize&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In the Fall of 1987, following an endowment made by then Dean Tom Traves, York University’s Faculty of Arts held their first faculty-wide essay contest. The competition was intended to recognize and celebrate undergraduate excellence in academic composition. As the Faculty of Arts evolved into the Faculty of Liberal Arts and Professional Studies, that essay contest became the LA&amp;PS Writing Prize.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Competition Description&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The LA&amp;PS Writing Prizes are open to all kinds of writing from students enrolled in LA&amp;PS courses, including case studies, administrative/executive reports, reviews of all kinds, non-fiction prose and formal essays (creative writing excepted). There are five categories: first through fourth year and also Major Research Project (MRP)/Undergraduate Thesis (if applicable). Any Course Director in LA&amp;PS is eligible to nominate a paper (one per course) in the appropriate category. Students’ papers are nominated using the year level of the course they were written for.&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/30507</handle><id>66</id><name>Lassonde School of Engineering</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>6</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/31416</handle><id>68</id><name>LGBTQ Home Care Access Project</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>12</countItems><introductoryText>A web archive for the LGBTQ Home Care Access Project can be found at this link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://digital.library.yorku.ca/wayback/20160915151024/http://www.yorku.ca/lgbthome/&quot;&gt;http://digital.library.yorku.ca/wayback/20160915151024/http://www.yorku.ca/lgbthome/&lt;/a&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/883</handle><id>10</id><name>Manuscripts of H.S. Harris</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>29</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;H. S. (Henry Silton) Harris, author and educator, was born on 11 April 1926 in Brighton England. He received his B. A. (Literae Humaniores) in classics and philosophy from Oxford University in 1949, his M. A. in 1952 and his Ph.D. (philosophy) in 1954 at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Following a teaching career at the University of Illinois and at Ohio State University (1951-1961), Harris joined the Philosophy Department at York University, Toronto in 1962. He served as Academic Dean of Glendon College, 1967-1969 and was awarded the title Distinguished Research Professor in 1984. He was elected to the Royal Society of Canada in 1988; received an Honorary Doctor of Letters from York University in June 2001 and was inducted the same year into York University's Founders' Honour Society in recognition of his contribution to York's early development. He retired from York in 1996 and lived in Victoria, British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Harris was a prolific scholar and an acknowledged authority on the philosophy of Giovanni Gentile and G.W.F. Hegel. He was the author of several books, articles and book chapters on Hegel including &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hegel's Development I: Toward the Sunlight (1770-1801),&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; published in 1972; &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hegel's Development II: Night Thoughts (Jena 1801-1806), &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  published in 1983; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hegel's Ladder (Volume 1: The Pilgrimage of Reason; Volume 2: The Odyssey of Spirit) &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  on Hegel's &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Phenomenology of Spirit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, published in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Harris prepared several translations with others of Hegel's works to which he added textual notes and introductions including &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;System of Ethical Life and First Philosophy of Spirit,&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (1979), &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lectures on the Philosophy of Religion,&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (1984-87) and &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Encyclopedia Logic with the Zusätze,&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (1991). He was unable to see to press manuscripts on Pre-platonic philosophy, Plato, Dante, Goethe, Blake and Hegel and a large collection of articles on philosophy and literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Harris died in Victoria on 13 March 2007.&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2712</handle><id>31</id><name>Ontario Committee on the Status of Women</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>25</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2590</handle><id>28</id><name>Refugee Research Network</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>296</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/9273</handle><id>43</id><name>Researcher Spotlights</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>124</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/26312</handle><id>57</id><name>Retrospective Theses and Dissertations (prior to 2013)</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>4</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/32384</handle><id>71</id><name>School of Health Policy and Management</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>54</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;h2&gt;Links to related collections&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://yorkspace.library.yorku.ca/xmlui/handle/10315/28600&quot;&gt;Electronic Theses and Dissertations - Critical Disability Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://yorkspace.library.yorku.ca/xmlui/handle/10315/30328&quot;&gt;Electronic Theses and Dissertations - Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/28562</handle><id>63</id><name>School of Social Work</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>0</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/2472</handle><id>24</id><name>School of the Arts, Media, Performance &amp; Design</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>60</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/27542</handle><id>60</id><name>SWORD Deposit</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>233</countItems><introductoryText>ETDs in this community are being checked for completeness and are in the process of being transferred to their respective collections under the FGS ETD collection umbrella.</introductoryText><shortDescription>Used only for SWORD Deposit by Adminstrator</shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/10039</handle><id>50</id><name>Symposia</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>3</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/6134</handle><id>39</id><name>The Homeless Hub</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>23</countItems><introductoryText>Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.homelesshub.ca/&quot;&gt; http://www.homelesshub.ca&lt;/a&gt; to access The Homeless Hub's entire library of scholarship on homelessness.</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/9857</handle><id>45</id><name>The William Westfall Canadian Studies Award</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>10</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;b&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The William Westfall Canadian Studies Prize&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;
&lt;br/&gt;&#xD;
The &lt;i&gt;William Westfall Canadian Studies Prize&lt;/i&gt; was created in honour of Professor William Westfall, a long-time member of Atkinson College and York University’s Department of Humanities. For many years, Professor Westfall alternately taught in and supervised the Canadian Studies Program on York’s Keele campus, inspiring many students in their study of Canada. In recent years, he has been a passionate and outspoken promoter of Canadian Studies at York, continually articulating the importance of ongoing development and new research in this interdisciplinary field. The William Westfall Canadian Studies Prize was created to honour Professor Westfall’s commitment to the Program, and his ongoing contributions to our understanding of Canada.&#xD;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xD;
&lt;b&gt;Competition Description&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xD;
&lt;br/&gt;&#xD;
The &lt;i&gt;William Westfall Canadian Studies Prize&lt;/i&gt; is a University wide contest, &#xD;
open to all students registered in 1000, 2000 and 3000 level Canadian-themed &#xD;
courses on both Keele and Glendon campuses. Accordingly, the competition &#xD;
encourages papers written in either French and English. &lt;br/&gt;&#xD;
&lt;br/&gt;&#xD;
Once each year, one winner is chosen at each year level. These winners receive &#xD;
an official transcript note and their essay published online and permanently &#xD;
available on York's website. A static URL of this faculty-reviewed essay will &#xD;
remain easily accessible to those considering applications for graduate and &#xD;
professional studies.</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/20772</handle><id>54</id><name>Vita Traductiva</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>55</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les Éditions québécoises de l’œuvre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;VITA TRADUCTIVA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;A joint initiative of the Research Group on Literary Translation in Canada at York University and the Éditions québécoises de l’oeuvre, &lt;em&gt;Vita Traductiva&lt;/em&gt; is an international peer-reviewed collection that gives priority to empirical studies of literary translation exchange and biographies of literary translators. The aim of the collection is to further our understanding of translation as &lt;em&gt;vita activa&lt;/em&gt;, to foster reciprocal cultural exchange, and to increase awareness of translation’s essential contribution to cultural diversity. The collection publishes in English and French, and welcomes scholarly studies on translation and translators in any language context by authors from around the world.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Initiative conjointe du Groupe de recherche sur la traduction littéraire au Canada à l’Université York et des Éditions québécoises de l’œuvre, dotée d’un comité scientifique international, la collection &lt;em&gt;Vita Traductiva&lt;/em&gt; publie en priorité des études empiriques sur la traduction littéraire comme moyen d’échange culturel ainsi que des biographies de traducteurs et de traductrices littéraires. La collection vise à faire mieux comprendre la traduction en tant que &lt;em&gt;vita activa&lt;/em&gt;, à favoriser des échanges réciproques et à faire mieux reconnaître l’apport essentiel de la traduction à la diversité culturelle. La collection publie en anglais et en français et accueille des recherches sur la traduction dans tous les contextes linguistiques de la part de chercheur(e)s de tous les pays du monde.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;EDITORIAL BOARD/ COMITÉ DE RÉDACTION&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Agnès Whitfield, York University, Canada, Director/Directrice &lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Rodica Dimitriu, Universitatea &quot;Alexandru Ioan Cuza,&quot; Romania/Roumanie&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Susan Ingram, York University, Canada &lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Michel Lord, University of Toronto, Canada&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Christine Raguet, Université Sorbonne Nouvelle - Paris 3, France&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Elzbieta Skibinska, Uniwersytet Wroclawski, Poland/Pologne&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Kristiina Taivalkoski-Shilov, Helsingin yliopisto, Finland/Finlande&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Priscila Uppal, York University, Canada&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;ADVISORY BOARD/ CONSEIL CONSULTATIF &lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Cecilia Alvstad, Universitetet i Oslo, Norway/Norvège&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Tiina Aunin, Tallinna Ülikool, Estonia/Estonie&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Astrid Fellner, Universität des Saarlandes, Germany/Allemagne &lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Vita Fortunati, Università di Bologna, Italy/Italie&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Madelena Gonzalez, Université d'Avignon, France&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Şehnaz Tahir Gürçağlar, Boğaziçi Üniversitesi, Turkey/Turquie &lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Margot Irvine, University of Guelph, Canada&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Zuzana Jettmarová, Univerzita Karlova v Praze, Czech Republic/République tchèque&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Genovaitė Kačiuškienė, Šiaulių universitetas, Lithuania/Lituanie&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Kaisa Koskinen, Itä-Suomen yliopisto, Finland/Finlande&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Regina Kvašytė, Šiaulių universitetas, Lithuania/Lituanie &lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Outi Paloposki, Turun yliopisto, Finland/Finlande&lt;BR/&gt;&#xD;
Alexandra Assis Rosa, Universidade de Lisboa, Portugal&#xD;
&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.editionsquebecoisesdeloeuvre.ca&quot;&gt;www.editionsquebecoisesdeloeuvre.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/31578</handle><id>69</id><name>York Centre for Asian Research</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>37</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://ycar.apps01.yorku.ca/&quot;&gt;York Centre for Asian Research (YCAR)&lt;/a&gt; is a community of York University researchers who are committed to analyzing the changing historical and contemporary dynamics of societies in Asia, understanding Asia’s place in the world, and studying the experiences of Asian communities in Canada and around the globe. Our inter-disciplinary membership includes faculty, students and other research associates from across the social sciences, humanities, health, education, creative/performing arts, law and business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Some common themes characterize much of the research that YCAR fosters and supports. First, we adopt an explicitly transnational approach to research, meaning that we seek to understand connections within Asia, between Asia and the rest of the world, and between Asia and its diasporas. Second, we value research that is based on extended field and archival research, language study and the long-term development of expertise. Third, we emphasize a critical and engaged model of scholarship, attentive to social justice agendas that seek to address exclusions or inequalities based class, gender, sexuality, ‘race’, caste, religion, region or environmental dispossession. Often, this involves collaboration with the communities being studied in the research process, and the mobilization of research findings to effect public education and social change. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The role of the Centre in the work of individual researchers is to create a space for interdisciplinary intellectual exchange, to provide administrative support for research projects, and to enrich student training through fieldwork and language awards and a graduate diploma programme. We also provide an access point for anyone interested in York expertise on Asia and Asian communities, and we actively seek to deliver research to the widest possible audience. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, YCAR continues a strong tradition of internationally recognized research in Asian Studies at York, pioneered since 1974 by the Joint Centre on Modern East Asia, and the Joint Centre for Asia Pacific Studies (both in collaboration with the University of Toronto).&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/1302</handle><id>23</id><name>York Centre for International and Security Studies</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>83</countItems><introductoryText>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yorku.ca/yciss/&quot;&gt;York Centre for International and Security Studies&lt;/a&gt; pursues a triple mandate of research, graduate teaching, and outreach. We undertake critical and theoretically-informed research that is guided by: a) a concern with the ethical-political dimensions of international security policies; and b) the assumption that the pursuit of security, defence, peace, and social justice requires the study of transnational and global forces in relation to local contexts and a range of social groups. The Centre, a research unit of York University, works and partners with academics, policymakers, practitioners, and activists across Canada and around the world. Our members include York faculty and graduate students, and visiting scholars from inside and outside Canada.&lt;/p&gt;</introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/13764</handle><id>51</id><name>York University Bookstore</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>3</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/939</handle><id>19</id><name>York University Libraries</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>252</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community><community><expand>parentCommunity</expand><expand>collections</expand><expand>subCommunities</expand><expand>logo</expand><expand>all</expand><handle>10315/30422</handle><id>65</id><name>Youth Research &amp; Evaluation eXchange (YouthREX)</name><type>community</type><copyrightText></copyrightText><countItems>1</countItems><introductoryText></introductoryText><shortDescription></shortDescription><sidebarText></sidebarText></community></communities>